So, that idea for how to rank webpages is
对网页进行排名与
the same idea as how we measure popularity of people.
衡量人们的受欢迎程度相似
But instead of thinking about friendships as the way
我们要衡量的是网页上的链接
to measure popularity, what we're measuring is links on the
而不是好友关系
web. When one page has a link to another
当某个网页有一个指向其他网页的链接时
page, well that indicates it's more likely that this other
则表明这个其他网页很有可能比较热门
page is popular, just like when someone is a friend,
就像某个人是好友一样
it indicates that the person they are friends with is
表明某人的好友更有可能比较受欢迎
more likely to be popular. So, the goal in ranking web
网页排名的目标是
pages is to get a measure of how popular are pages,
根据链接到相关网页的其他网页
based on the other pages that link to it but we
衡量该网页的热门程度
have the same issue with popularity then not all links are
但是我们遇到了和受欢迎程度一样的问题
the same. That a link from a page that's really important
并非所有的链接都一样 某个非常重要的网页发出的链接
counts for a lot more than a link from a page
比不重要的网页发出的链接占比要大很多
that is not important. So, if the New York Times has
假设《纽约时报》上有个链接指向你的网页
a link to your page, that counts for a lot more than
同时假设你妈妈设置了一个网页
if your mom sets up a web page and puts a
并在上面放置了指向你的网页的链接
link to your page in it. Unless your mom is Lady
那么纽约时报的链接肯定更具分量
Gaga, in which case her link probably counts for more. So,
除非你妈妈是 Lady Gaga 这种情况下 她给出的链接更具分量
another way of thinking about this is what we're trying to model
另一种思考方法是我们要模拟
is a random web surfer. So, our random web surfer has
一个随机网络服务器
some set of pages that they know about. And those pages
该服务器具有一些已知的网页
have links to other pages. Some pages might have a lot
这些网页具有指向其他网页的链接
of links. Some pages might just have one link. Some pages might
某些网页可能具有很多链接 某些可能只有一个链接
have no links. So, one way to think about this
某些可能没有链接
is that we're trying to model a random web surfer. The
一种思考方式是尝试模拟一个随机网络服务器
web surfer starts knowing about some pages. And she picks
该服务器开始了解一些网页
one page at random, let's say she picks this page. And
它随机选择一个网页 假设选择了这个网页
then, when she's on that page, she picks a random
然后转到该网页上 随机选择一个链接
link and follows that links. Whoops, this was a bad starting
点击该链接 糟糕 这个起始网页不太好
page. It actually has no out links. So, then, she picks
它实际上没有向外的链接
another random page. Let's say she picks this one. She follows
然后选择另一个随机网页 假设选择了这个
the link from that page, and now she got to the
点击该链接
page with no links again. Let's say she picked a better starting
再次转到没有链接的网页 假设选择了更好的起始点
point. Let's say she randomly picked this one. Now she's got
假设随机选择了这个网页
two links to follow. She randomly picks one of those. She follows
现在可以点击两个链接 随机选择一个
it. She gets to a new page. She randomly picks a
转到新的网页
link from that page, in this case, it only had one, and
随机选择该网页上的链接 这种情况下 只有一个链接
in this case, it seems we have a bit of a
在这种情况下 我们似乎遇到了问题
problem, because all of the starting pages eventually lead into this one,
因为所有的起始网页最终都转到这个网页
which has no outgoing links. So, we'll think about how to
它没有向外的链接
solve that problem later, but we can think of what our
稍后我们将思考如何解决该问题
random web surfer is doing, is picking random pages, following links,
现在我们可以认为随机网络服务器所做的是选择随机网页
and what we want to measure is the popularity of a page.
点击链接 我们想要衡量某个网页的受欢迎程度
And that's the probability that she reaches that given page, starting
即从这些随机网页抵达给定网页的概率
from these random pages. So, if you did this over and
如果不断执行这一流程
over again, and you counted the number of times you reached
算出抵达每个网页的次数
each page, that would give you a measure of that page's popularity.
就可以得出该网页的受欢迎程度
So, this is very similar to the popularity function. We're
和 popularity 函数很相似
going to define a function that we'll call the rank of
我们将定义一个网页排名函数
the page. And, like the way we defined the popularity
和定义 popularity 函数一样
function, it's going to have two inputs. It's going to have a
有两个输入
time step, and it's going to have the page which we'll
一个是时间步长 一个是网页 用 URL 表示
use a URL for. And the output of rank will
rank() 的输出是一个数字
be some number. Except for we'll define for time step
但是我们将定义时间步长 0
zero. This is our base case, and we're going to find all
这是我们的基础条件
the ranks have value one. We'll actually change
所有排名值为 1
that shortly, but we'll start out think of it,
稍后做更改 我们先假设所有排名
all the ranks having value one, like we
值都是 1
did with the popularity scores. And then we'll define
就像受欢迎程度得分一样
the value of the rank at time step t for any given URL. Just like we defined
然后将定义任何给定 URL 在时间步长 t 时的排名值
the popularity score. It's going to be the sum of
就像定义受欢迎程度得分一样
all the pages that are friends with this page,
等于与该网页是好友的网页排名之和
and what it means for our webpage to be friends
网页与其他网页是好友是指
with another page is that it has a link to it.
具有指向该网页的链接
So, this is going to be for all the pages that
也就是存在的链接到该 URL 的所有网页
exist that have some link to that URL, or its friends.
即它的好友
And so, we're going to go through each of those pages.
我们可以查看每个网页
We'll call them inlinks instead of friends. We're going to go through
称之为 inlinks 而不是 friends
those and we're going to sum up the ranks that we got
我们将查看这些网页 并算出时间步长 t-1 时
for those pages at time t minus one. So, this is
这些网页的排名之和
our first model of popularity on, of webpages. This is exactly
这就是网页的第一个受欢迎程度模型
the same as the model we had of popularity for people.
这和人的受欢迎程度模型完全一样
It's not going to work that well yet and one of the
但是效果不太好
reasons it's not going to work that well is some pages
原因之一是某些网页
might have lots of links. And if a page has lots
可能有很多的链接
of links, the value of each one of it's links should
如果某个网页有很多的链接 则它的链接的每个值
be diminished. It shouldn't have the same value as the page
都应该减小 不应该和只有一个链接
that only has one link that links to this URL. Maybe that
指向该 URL 的网页值相同
should be the same case for a friend's popularity, if
或许这和好友的受欢迎程度差不多
someone has lots of friends, each friend is less valuable.
如果某人有很多好友 则每个好友的重要性都更低
Whereas someone who only has a small number of friends
但是如果某人只有一小部分好友
has lots of time for each friend. So this is the
则有很多时间陪每位好友
way we're going to model web popularity. We don't want
我们就这样表示网页受欢迎程度
to just give the same score to each link. We're
我们不希望给每个链接设定相同的得分
going to change this by dividing by the number of outlinks.
为此 我们将除以向外链接的数量
So, if a page has many outgoing links, the value to
如果某个网页有很多向外链接
the pages that it links to is less for each page. So,
则它链接到的每个网页的值会降低
a page that's just a long list of lots of links won't
如果某个网页是一个长长的链接列表
have that much influence on the rankings. If a page only has
则对排名没太多影响
a few outgoing links, well then, they are worth more. So, what are
如果某个网页只有少数几个向外链接 那么重要性更高
going to do, is divide this by the number of out links from
我们要做的是将这个除以 p 的向外链接数量
p. So, each of the p pages, right? These will be the
即每个 p 网页 对吧？
values of p, as they go through the inlinks of URL. We
这些将是经历 URL 的内部链接时 p 的值
are going to sum up the rank that we got on the previous time
我们将对上一时间步长的排名求和
step and divide that by the number of out links.
并除以向外链接的数量